Abhishek Deshmukh (1) Featured

Product Support Executive seeking assignments in Application support, Software Testing, Program Management, Manual Testing, Application Security Testing, UAT Testing, Oracle, Java, Tomcat, SQL Server, Weblogic, Toad, Visual Studio



Current Designation: Product Support Executive-IT Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 1 Month(s)

Current Company: NCS Softsolution Pvt. Ltd Notice Period: Currently Serving Notice Period

Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Current Location: Mumbai

Pref. Location: Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Key Skills: Product Support Executive, Application Support, Software Testing, Program Management, Manual Testing, Application Security Testing, UAT Testing, Oracle, Java, Tomcat, SQL Server, Weblogic, Toad, Visual Studio

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 19-Jan-21 Last Modified: 19-Jan-21

Summary

Technical Support Engineer with 4 years experience in a sensitive corporate environment. I am proficient in MS-SQL, Oracle, Software Testing - Manual testing, Application Security testing, Project implementation, deployment and building & maintaining professional relationships. Have an Associate?s Degree in Computer Engineering.

Presently associated with NCS Soft Solution Itd, Chennai and Working at client location at SBI Global IT Center, Belapur, Navi Mumbai, HDFC Bank Kanjurmarg as Product Support Executive

NCS Soft is a product development company primarily focused on developing products for banking and financial sector. eTHIC ? Risk Based Audit Application. eTHIC is an industry-defining solution that reshapes the way auditing & compliance management is executed in the BFSI sector.

Projects: In SBI 4 modules and HDFC eTHIC?s 1 module Implemented? Retail Operation Audit Application, , Audit Exception, RBIA, CAS, Revenue Audit, Management Audit, CSR (Life cycle Management) etc.

Work Experience

NCS Softsolution Pvt. Ltd as Product Support Executive-IT Aug 2018 to Till Date

Client: SBI Global IT Center, Navi Mumbai and HDFC Bank, MUmbai

Platform used: Windows server, 2008, 2012, Windows 7/8

Tools used: SQL Server Management Studio 2012/14/16, Oracle 12C,11G DB, Apache Tomcat Server, Oracle Weblogic Server, eTHIC- Retail Operation Audit Application, RBS Compliance Portal, Audit Exception portal, CSR (Life cycle Management), Ticket Portal

Responsibilities:

Handling database and application related issues and queries and Generating data Report and handling database queries on DDL, DML and DCL, Procedures, Joins etc. depends on table?s creation from database as per client requirements. Requirements gathering and analysis, Improve product quality, reduce defects by supporting best quality practices and implement effective process improvement methods, Analyzing recurring issues and raise requirement

Proficiency in Application Manual testing, Regression testing, UAT Testing, Database Testing, Sanity testing, Database Secure Configuration, Server and tomcat secure configuration, contribution in Application Security review resolution and explanation

Active contribution in the UAT testing, troubleshooting & debugging of the application, Product-implementation in UAT and production, application maintenance and enhancement support to eThic.

Active contribution in VAPT, Server security patch installation, SQL patch updating and Version up-gradation, SSL certification and server secure configuration (SCD).

Application Performance monitoring, logs analyzing, Java melody report, DB Backup, logs backup and restore of database

and Source code, contribution Server PD ?DR activity, bugs Tracking, Server and source code changes and patch update Coordinating with the development team for critical issues, new requirements and change request related to application Product implementation and deployment, Server Configuration and maintenance

Thinkapp Solution Ltd as Application Support Engineer

Dec 2017 to Jun 2018

Client: Yes Bank., Mumbai

Projects: In Cashin collection and disbursement, IMAC, ASBA application

Platform used: Windows server 2003, 2008, 2012, Windows 7/8

Tools used: SQL Server Management Studio 2005/8/12, IIS Server, web Application

Responsibilities:

Cashin Collection and Disbursement Application is used for Corporate Clients in various units and PAN India Branches.

Handling database queries on DDL, DML and DCL commands depends on table and data.

Database backup and restore

Coordinating with the development team for Critical technical issues.

Performing RCA and fixing user and application issues along with deploying patches where necessary

Guiding and resolving issue in Cashin collection and Disbursement for regular basis

Preparing & Executing Test Cases, UAT Testing

Testing on new updates on portal as well as on offline server of SQL.

Provide data for Technology & Operations (YES BANK India) for RBI & AUDIT requirement

Solving Portal related Queries of the client NOC centers

MyPOS Technology Pvt Ltd as System Support Executive

Dec 2016 to Dec 2017

Projects: Retail-whizz is an integrated E.R.P solution, based on ORACLE RDBMS technology and tools. Barcode

Adapted Stock & Inventory Control System

Platform used: Windows server 2003, 2008, 2012, Windows 7/8

Tools used: Toad, Oracle SQL Developer

Responsibilities:

Resolving technical errors in the Oracle database and ensuring that the bugs are removed successful.

Developed several custom tablespace structure interact with data tables and schema.

Database backup and restore

Install application and Oracle database in client server machine

Assisting clients in recovering and data mirroring the database in case of data loss.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from North Maharashtra University, Jalgaon in 2016

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:

Diploma

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
sql server management studio			
Oracle, Tomcat Server, D2K,Toad			
Weblogic, Visual Studio, Basic JAVA			
Linux, Windows Server			
MSSQL Server, Oracle Database			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	

1/22/2021	https://freesearch.naukri.com/preview/printResume?uname=82833cd9d7d6fd97a3729a302d0354cb0a540153181501170145445				
English					
Hindi					
Marathi					

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No

Work Authorization

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time